<?xml version="1.0"?>
<metadata xml:lang="en"><Esri><CreaDate>20180522</CreaDate><CreaTime>08461300</CreaTime><ArcGISFormat>1.0</ArcGISFormat><ArcGISstyle>FGDC CSDGM Metadata</ArcGISstyle><SyncOnce>TRUE</SyncOnce><ModDate>20230518</ModDate><ModTime>16463700</ModTime><scaleRange><minScale>150000000</minScale><maxScale>5000</maxScale></scaleRange><ArcGISProfile>FGDC</ArcGISProfile></Esri><tool name="Projector" displayname="Projector" toolboxalias="ProfileProject" xmlns=""><arcToolboxHelpPath>c:\arcgis\pro\Resources\Help\gp</arcToolboxHelpPath><parameters><param name="project_points" displayname="Point Feature Class with points to be projected:" type="Required" direction="Input" datatype="Feature Layer" expression="project_points"><dialogReference>&lt;DIV STYLE="text-align:Left;"&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Point feature class containing the points you want to assign a river distance to.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</dialogReference></param><param name="distance_points" displayname="Point Feature Class with river distance:" type="Required" direction="Input" datatype="Feature Layer" expression="distance_points"><dialogReference>&lt;DIV STYLE="text-align:Left;"&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;A point feature class with points along the river centerline. They should be spaced at regular intervals and have distance along the river stored in a short integer, long integer, double, or float field. The built in "Generate Points Along A Line" geoprocessing tool in ArcGIS Pro 3.1.1 and later can automatically add river distance points at regular intervals if you have a line feature class for the river centerline.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</dialogReference></param><param name="distance_field" displayname="River Distance Field:" type="Required" direction="Input" datatype="Field" expression="distance_field"><dialogReference>&lt;DIV STYLE="text-align:Left;"&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Short integer, long integer, float, or double field containing distance along the river.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</dialogReference></param><param name="zone_polygons" displayname="Polygon Feature Class with zones:" type="Optional" direction="Input" datatype="Feature Layer" expression="{zone_polygons}"><dialogReference>&lt;DIV STYLE="text-align:Left;"&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Polygon feature class with zones to split up the projection. Points to be projected will be matched with river distance falling within their corresponding zone. This feature class must have a text field with unique values for each zone. If you do not specify zones, the entire river will be matched with all points to be projected.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</dialogReference></param><param name="zone_field" displayname="Zone Name Field:" type="Optional" direction="Input" datatype="Field" expression="{zone_field}"><dialogReference>&lt;DIV STYLE="text-align:Left;"&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Text field from the polygon feature class with zones. This field will drive pairing of river distance points to be projected. Each zone should be uniquely named. Required if a polygon feature class with zones is specified.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</dialogReference></param><param name="output_projected_points" displayname="Output feature class:" type="Required" direction="Output" datatype="Feature Class" expression="output_projected_points"><dialogReference>&lt;DIV STYLE="text-align:Left;"&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Name and location for the output projected points. This feature class will contain river distance and elevation values.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</dialogReference></param><param name="DEM" displayname="Raster or mosaic with elevation values (DEM):" type="Required" direction="Input" datatype="Mosaic Layer or Raster Layer" expression="DEM"><dialogReference>&lt;DIV STYLE="text-align:Left;"&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Elevation values from this raster/mosaic will be added to each point to be projected.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</dialogReference></param><param name="remove_nulls" displayname="Remove projected points with no river distance value" type="Optional" direction="Input" datatype="Boolean" expression="{remove_nulls}"><dialogReference>&lt;DIV STYLE="text-align:Left;"&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The default is to keep all projected points.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</dialogReference></param><param name="include_projection_lines" displayname="Include Projection Lines" type="Optional" direction="Input" datatype="Boolean" expression="{include_projection_lines}"><dialogReference>&lt;DIV STYLE="text-align:Left;"&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This option will create a line feature class connected projected points to their corresponding river distance point. It can be useful for visualizing the projection output. The default is to include projection lines.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</dialogReference></param><param name="output_projection_lines_fc" displayname="Output Projection Line Feature Class:" type="Optional" direction="Output" datatype="Feature Class" expression="{output_projection_lines_fc}"><dialogReference>&lt;DIV STYLE="text-align:Left;"&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Name and location of the feature class that will contain projection lines. Required if Include Projection Lines is checked.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</dialogReference></param></parameters><summary>&lt;DIV STYLE="text-align:Left;"&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This tool will create a longitudinal river profile for an input point feature class, hereafter referred to as points to be projected. To accomplish this, you need an additional point feature class spaced at regular intervals along a river centerline. That feature class also needs a field that stores distance along the river. Hereafter, that feature class is called river distance points.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;If you have a river centerline stored in a line feature class, you can use the Generate Points Along a Line geoprocessing tool in ArcGIS Pro 3.1.1 and later to create evenly spaced points complete with distance along the river.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This tool will take your points to be projected, and use the Near tool to determine the closest river distance point. It will then add the river distance values to your points to be projected. Finally, it will extract the elevation value from an input DEM at each point to be projected.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The output feature class can be graphed as Elevation vs Distance to create a longitudinal profile.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The tool also gives you the option of using zones. With polygon zones, the tool will first use Split to section off the river distance points and the points to be projected. Near will then be run on each pair within each zone, and the results combined into one output feature class. This can be helpful for a sinuous river to help control exactly where points are projected along the river.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;There is an option to remove projected points with no river distance values.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Finally, there is an option to include Projection Lines, which will create a line feature class connecting projected points to their corresponding river distance point. It can be used to evaluate the output of the Near analysis and any zones used.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</summary></tool><dataIdInfo><idCitation><resTitle>Projector</resTitle></idCitation></dataIdInfo><distInfo><distributor><distorFormat><formatName>ArcToolbox Tool</formatName></distorFormat></distributor></distInfo><mdHrLv><ScopeCd value="005"/></mdHrLv><mdDateSt Sync="TRUE">20230518</mdDateSt></metadata>
